SEAN STICKLAND

Full Stack Developer

021-829-780 • EMAIL • LINKEDIN • GITHUB • PORTFOLIO

The project I'm most proud of at the moment is a social drawing game called Pictophone.

ABOUT ME

I'm a software developer with 9 years experience in IT Support. This year I graduated from <u>Dev Academy</u>, an intense TypeScript based coding bootcamp, where I graduated as "one of our most advanced students," as described by the lead teacher.

To upskill further, I'm currently finishing a course on Python and cloud infrastructure run by AWS and Unitec, called <u>AWS re/Start.</u>

Combining my extensive industry experience in the IT world, with my enthusiasm and aptitude for software development and cloud computing, I'm eager to join a high-performing development team where I can contribute my skills and continue to learn.

SKILLS & EXPERTISE

- Proficient in TypeScript, Node.js, React, Redux, HTML, CSS, Tailwind, MySQL, Python.
- Skilled with Git, GitHub, code reviews, and RESTful APIs.
- Experienced in both AWS and Azure cloud infrastructure.
- Have written extensive unit tests using Jest and other testing libraries.
- Due to many years working IT in software companies, I am not afraid of asking questions, admitting when I don't know something, or finding answers on my own.
- Have developed automation scripts in Batch, PowerShell, and Azure Process Automation to streamline IT tasks and increase efficiency.

EXPERIENCE

Part Time Work and Side Projects | May 2023 - Present

- Studying and building side projects while working part time maintaining WordPress sites.
- Currently finishing <u>AWS re/Start</u>, a course that covers building AWS cloud infrastructure using Python.
- Created and deployed <u>Pictophone</u>, a Pictionary/Telephone hybrid online game.

Dev Academy | Jan 2023 - May 2023 |

Student

- Coached and mentored less experienced students.
- Made various projects in React and Express, while also focusing on human skills like providing feedback, collaboration, and working in agile teams.
- Led a team of 5 in creating a <u>restaurant ordering app</u>, where I took responsibility for coding the back-end and helped with much of the front-end.

Tekne LTD | Dec 2020 - Dec 2022 |

ICT Technician

• Tekne is a significantly smaller company which fostered a greater sense of individual ownership over challenges and a wider spectrum of tasks to tackle.

- Using Azure Process Automation, I automated the offboarding of leaving employees, saving hours a week, and preventing disgruntled employee incidents.
- Developed strong organizational and communication skills needed to effectively schedule and manage the IT needs of several businesses across NZ.
- Collaborated with team members and clients to solve complex IT challenges, which further developed problem-solving skills and built strong relationships.
- Showed the ability to rapidly adapt to new clients, environments, and systems.

Vista Entertainment | Apr 2019 - Nov 2020 |

ICT Technician

- Stayed up to date with industry trends and best practices to improve system performance and security, effectively managing risks.
- Wrote Batch and PowerShell automation scripts to expedite computer setup processes.
- Collaborated with developers to resolve routine hardware and software issues, further developing my technical and problem-solving skills.

Sony Mobile, Oceania | Feb 2015 - Dec 2018 |

Service Warranty & Training Manager

 Managed staff training, repairs, refunds, and dealt with tribunal cases against Sony.

Sony Electronics, Oceania | Oct 2013 - May 2015 |

Customer Support Representative, IT Specialist

Customer facing consumer support for VAIO laptops.

EDUCATION

2023 - Dev Academy Aotearoa

Certificate in Applied Software Development

2010 - Auckland University of Technology

• Certificate in Computer & Mathematical Sciences

This included courses on Java and calculus

ACHIEVEMENTS

During my graduation ceremony at Dev Academy, my teacher specifically called out my aptitude for programming and leadership.

PERSONAL

In my spare time, apart from coding word games, I enjoy playing guitar, trivia shows, karaoke, watching terrible action movies, and seeing indie rock bands. I like teaching, learning and making people laugh. I'm not afraid of admitting when I'm wrong or asking questions when I don't know something.

REFERENCES

See below from Dev Academy. Others available upon request.

Level 5, 12 Morgan Street Level 2, 275 Cuba Street Auckland 1011 Wellington 6011

28 July 2023

To Sean's future employers,

Sean attended and successfully completed the Dev Academy Bootcamp at the Auckland campus in 2023.

As a Lead teacher, I taught and worked closely with Sean throughout this time and I regarded him as one of our most advanced students. He applied himself to every challenge and did so with curiosity.

He seemed to have a natural talent for programming and I was always impressed with the quality of his work. He tended to research his approach well and deliver features in a timely manner. He would also consider proper functionality as well as edge-cases. For example, he delivered server-side API code using database returning arrays to improve performance. This was something he discovered himself.

Sean was an ambitious and reliable teammate among his peers and the quality of their final project reflected his influence. This included presentations which he delivered with confidence.

I appreciated his straight-forward communication style, especially when it came to giving and receiving feedback. Lastly, I enjoyed his sometimes twisted sense of humour.

I recommend Sean as a well-rounded, talented developer and wish him success in his career and chosen craft.

Sincerely,

Alex Coaton (Lead Teacher)

devacademy.co.nz

